One of the traditional origami pieces is the lily.
And my name is Robert Segundo and today I'm going to teach you how to do this.
What I'm going to do is I'm just going to unfold this guy here, and this already good and pre-creased.
And make it easy and we can run through this real quick.
So what we're going to do is we're really going to start off with the traditional water bomb base, and if you really don't know how to do that, there's other videos that I have out that you can go and look and it's going to look basically look like this.
And then from there what you're going to do is you're going to take the legs of your water bomb base, you're going to open it, and squash fold it like so.
And you're going to do that to all four sides.
Oops.
There you go.
Just open this up, and this, squash fold it, open it back.
Squash fold it like so, and now after all your sides are folded what you're going to do is basically going to rabbit ear these sections by taking and folding the bottom corners in to your center line, then opening back up and folding up like so all the way 'til you form this diamond shape here.
What you're going to do is you're going to basically do that on all sides.
Just going to go ahead and use my pre-creases to go ahead and do that real quickly.
There we go.
And once you've done that you just take and fold all your legs down, like so.
Open it up here, where is it, there it is.
Hold it down like so.
Then we're going to do is this is your open end up here, so what we're going to do is at your closed end, with the bottom here, we're just going to take and we're going to fold each of these petal corners over to the center like so.
So, do it on all four sides, turn it up, all four sides.
Like so.
Now that all of these are folded like this you're just going to take your petal, that's what this is right here, you're going to fold it all the way down where you leave those guys sticking up like that, flip it over.
Do it on all four sides.
Then basically after it's done all you got to do is release your petals, then you open all four of them up, your water lily just takes shape all on its own.
Well, not really a water lily, but just your lily.
There you have it, your simple lily.
Play around with the origami, have fun and enjoy.